# **Richard Eldridge**

## **SUMMARY:**

Software Developer with 2 years fullstack experience. Adept at back-end scripting and object-oriented programming from numerous API integrations and modernizing legacy programming. Additional knowledge and skills in e-commerce business operations. working with remote team members. professional communication and troubleshooting complex problems all refined from working under individuals with decades of experience.

## **CONTACT:**

Richardaeld@gmail.com GitHub

LinkedIn

## **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

## Atlanta Network Technologies (ANTonline)

Smyrna, GA | Jun 2022 - current

Software Developer I

API Integration & Maintenance

Implemented new 3<sup>rd</sup> party integrations using PHP scripts with OOP and MVC architecture. This Reduced maintenance time by 50% compared to legacy integrations.

Update & Extend Infrastructure

- Created a Linux and PHP solution to ensure synchronous script function in an autonomous scheduled environment.
- Used Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) to unify front and back-end code to reduce code complexity and repetition for all logistic related views. This reduced maintenance time by over 80%.
- Designed and implemented an API that allowed JavaScript (JS) to utilize and call PHP classes and functions through the JS Fetch API.

#### Create Reports

- Developed a PHP and JavaScript report architecture that allowed reports to be reactive without refresh and reduced code required by 50%leveraging an API and class architecture I designed.
- This design greatly improved the user experience and allowed for a singlpoint of code truth which reduced bugs and required testing time.
- Modernized legacy reports to Model View Controller (MVC) and OOP architecture to decrease future maintenance time by 75% by improving code readability.
- Created scripts to upload and ingest CSV, XLXS files into Database.

## Monitor & Report Logs

- Interpreted system logs to identify new customer facing bugs before they were reported thus saving PR and preserving customers.
- Proactively identified and resolved several critical errors, including checkout issues, before customers reported them.

## SGPS ShowRig, Inc.

Norcross, GA | Feb. 2015 - Jun 2020

Department Head of Motor and Power Control

## **EDUCATION:**

## Software Development Diploma

\*EU Accredited RQF Level 5 Diploma Code Institute May 2020 - Nov. 2021

## **SKILLS:**

## Languages

JavaScript

Java

PHP

 $CSS \, / \, HTML$ 

Python

## Tools

Linux

Git

Google Meets

Docker

Visual Studio Code

#### Databases

Percona MySQL

PostgreSQL

Mongo DB

## Libraries

Node.js Express.js

React.js

## API Integrations

Walmart

FedEx

Endicia

eBay Amazon

Target

## **ACCOLADES:**

#### Hack-a-thon Awards:

1st Place Award- 2022 3rd Place Award- 2021

# Code Institute Projects with Merit Distinction:

Fat Raccoon Website Eldridge Music Emporium

Bachelor's of Computer Science Kennesaw State University